Okay, I'll say it. Building agents is
the new SAS. I mean, we saw billions of
dollars of value creation during the SAS
era. People, founders, 21 years old, 24
years old, you name it, come up with SAS
ideas that changed their lives. Of
course, not everyone was successful, but
this is a new wave that's happening. And
[music] I want you to understand what
this wave is, how you can take advantage
of it, how you can build startups in
this space. And in this episode, I'm
basically going to clearly explain this
entire agents is the new SAS
opportunity. By the end of this, you're
going to understand the playbook. You're
going to understand how to find the
niche. You're going to understand how to
pick the workflow, how to, you know,
build your first agent, how to prove it
works, how you can package it like SAS,
and how you can basically sell these
agents as labor. And it's really
important because that that labor point
because labor is a multi- trillion
dollar market, right? So I think why
people say agents is bigger than SAS is
because the total addressable market for
agents is just way bigger. You know it's
human capital. And I wanted to just
[music] do an episode where I explain
everything step by step just clearly for
people who are interested in building
agents who are who are interested in
selling agents [music]
and who are you know just want their
creative juices flowing around this.
This is for anyone who wants to build a
business or who just want wants to be
more productive. This episode is for
you. [music]
[music]
>> So the first thing you need to
understand is the product is the job. So
you know the mental model I have for
this is SAS sells software agent SAS
sells work. A normal SAS product says
here is a tool a team could use
basically. Um but an agent SAS product
will say here is a job your team no
longer has to do by hand and then you're
selling that service. So it sounds like
a a small change but it's a it's a
really big mindset change for the
customer and for you the person who's
going to bu be building it. So take uh
restaurants for example. You know a
restaurant wakes up thinking our phone
is ringing during you know dinner time
um and the host is busy right dealing
with you know seating people. People are
asking the same questions. We're missing
reservations and private dining calls
are getting lost. So, they're basically
missing out on lost revenue. This is why
a company like, you know, Slang AI is
interesting. Basically, it's an AI
superhost for restaurants. Not
affiliate. I just think it's an
interesting, you know, example. Uh, it
answers inbound calls. It handles guest
questions. It manages reservations. It
routes VIPs. It alerts staff about high
priority topics like private dining or
guest complaints. And it integrates with
systems like Open Table and Yelp and
stuff like that. I'll give you another
example. home services, a plumbing
company, HVAC company, a roofing
company, pest control company, miss
calls, you know, jobs are booked,
customers followed up with, dispatches
are less overwhelmed, more revenue from
the same demand if they integrate
something that picks up their phone
24/7. You know, an example of a startup
that's doing this is same day. So they
focus on home services and then they
basically sell these AI, you know,
dispatchers, sales agents, receptionists
that answer calls, respond to texts,
books jobs, reschedule. Again, the
product is the job. These examples
matter because they're just
understandable. And so when you're
thinking about coming up with an idea
for a startup here, think about I handle
this one annoying job better than a
junior employee, faster than an agency,
and it's cheaper than adding headcount.
That's the mental model I think that you
should be thinking about. The second
step I have here is pick a workflow with
a paycheck attached.
So you know, how do you find the right
agent idea? You want to start with the
paycheck, right? If people are already
paying for the work, they're paying an
employee, they're paying an agency, a
receptionist, a coordinator, dispatcher,
they there's an opportunity to sell that
service cheaper and then unload some of
that work that that person is doing to
do more high highly creative creative
work. So a good agent workflow has five
traits. Um the first is it happens all
the time. So daily is good but hourly is
better. Uh you know every inbound lead
uh every call, every tech ticket, every
quote request, every appointment, every
order, every maintenance request.
Second, it has to have a clear finish
line. Uh the job got booked, uh the
ticket got categorized, uh the refund
got approved, uh the vendor got
scheduled. Um the customer got a useful
answer. Uh third uh if it touches
already software. So if it touches Gmail
or Slack or Shopify, HubSpot, Zenes,
Stripe, um agents need these tools so
they can use it and they also need the
context that they can read. The fourth
is the edge cases are actually really
annoying um but they're learnable. So if
a workflow is too basic um basically the
problem is basic automation you know
zaps and stuff like that can do it um if
it's pure human judgment uh the first
version will break. So the sweet spot is
repetitive work with enough judgment
that AI can help. Uh the fifth is the
buyer can feel the loss. missed calls,
slow replies, drop leads, uh empty
calendar slots, uh expensive humans
doing low value uh coordination. So, if
this is, you know, you know, if you want
to start a business here, here, what's a
first rep to get started? Well, pick one
niche and write down 20 jobs people
complain about. Um, if it's roofers, you
know, maybe it's missed calls, uh,
financing questions, insurance
paperwork, appointment reminders. If
it's med spas, it's maybe lead
qualifications or no-show recovery,
membership upselles. Um, if it's Shopify
brands, maybe it's uh returns, uh,
exchanges, uh, wholesale lead
follow-ups. And then you want to score
each job on five things. Um, how often
does it happen? How expensive is the
pain? How easy it how easy is it to know
when the job is done? Uh what tools does
it need access to? And who already owns
the budget? And that is where agent SAS
starts. So you want to start with the
job that has a paycheck attached. Super
super key point here.
Um once you've done that you actually
and this is this is the thing that a lot
of people miss you you actually want to
shadow the human before you build. So
once you find the job right you you
you've identify what the job is before
you like prompt before you start coding
just shadow a human being who does the
job. Uh, I know a lot of founders want
to skip this. Um, but it's usually
what's going to help you get, you know,
an unfair advantage, an insight into
building an agent that is high quality.
So, just watch someone do the job 10 to
20 jobs. Ask them to screen record it.
Um, ask them to narrate what they're
doing. Uh, ask them what makes a case
easy. Uh, ask them what makes a case
weird. Um, what did they check before
they make a decision? and ask them, you
know, where the mistakes happen.
Basically, you're looking for the real
workflow. Um, and even if you've done
these tasks before, having having it,
you know, fresh in your memory, is just
going to be super super helpful when
you're building out this. So, you know,
for example, a restaurant host, if they
answer, "What time are you open?" Uh,
the real workflow is actually deeper
than that. um they know when the kitchen
closes, which tables are good for
strollers, uh when the patio is closed,
how to handle a VIP, uh and you know
when to route to a priv inquiry. So the
detail is the product. Um and when
you're specking out your your agent, you
know, I think it should have seven key
parts. What wakes the agent up? What
context does it need? What tools can it
use? What is it allowed to do itself?
Where does it need approval? When should
it escalate and and bring a human in the
loop there? And what does success look
like? And if you understand all those
things, um you're, you know, you're not
just going to build an agent slop,
right? We want to build agents that are
high quality, that are exceptional, that
do the work as well, if not better than
humans, and way more consistently, and
that's what people are going to pay for.
So, uh, really helpful to just sort of
internalize that. Now, you're going to
want, uh, step four is you're going to
want to build the smallest useful agent.
You know, I call it the minimal useful
agent, the MUA.
Most people hear agent and imagine a
fully autonomous employee. Um, and
that's how you you get these demos that
you see on Twitter. Uh, and they don't
really work and it ends up being a bad
business. Um, you want to start smaller
actually. So, there are four good first
versions. The first is a draft and
approve agent. So, it reads context. It
drafts the reply, the quote, the summary
or the next step. A human approves it.
Uh so this is great when there's
workflow risk um maybe there's
creativity involved uh approval
processes that that sort of thing. The
second is a triage agent. So it
classifies inbound work and routes it to
the right place maintenance requests uh
billing issue or you know refund that
sort of thing. The third is a
coordinator agent. So this goes between
systems and people. So, it'll check
availability, it'll send reminders, it
asks for missing info, um, and it keeps
the work moving basically. Um, and the
fourth the fourth is the bounded action
agent. So, it can do a specific thing
under clear rules. You know, book an
appointment, send a follow-up, you know,
process a refund under $50. These are
the sorts of things you'll you'll now
see. You'll notice it in the wild. Like
for example, with Uber Eats, you order
something and your salad doesn't arrive,
automatically you'll get the refund um
based on an agent that will do it. So
that's basically the the ladder here. Uh
when you're building the the minimum
useful agent, uh draft, triage, uh
coordinate, and act. I was looking at
Anthropic's agent guidance uh recently
and they made a really uh important
point, a really important simple point.
They said many agent problems should
start actually as workflows. So a
workflow follows a predictable path. An
agent decides more dynamically. Founders
should earn autonomy by starting with a
predictable path and adding judgment
only when it creates value. So if I were
building this, I would start with one
workflow and one promise. For example,
like we answered miss we answer missed
calls for roofers uh and book qualified
jobs or we triage maintenance requests
for property managers and schedule the
right vendor. We handle reservation
calls for restaurants and alert staff
when a human should jump in. Um that's
enough. That's really enough. And one
workflow that works enough is is good
enough for day one. And it's going to
help just like build confidence not just
in you that it's working, but also in
this customer. Cuz keep in mind, people
are buying agents for the first time
ever. So they they want to they don't
want all of it at the same time,
especially if you're not Microsoft or
you're not Salesforce. So step five in
building an agent is the product wrapper
is what makes it a SAS. So you don't
want to just build a cool automation.
And I think what separates a cool
automation from a real agent first SAS
product is the agent does the work but
the rapper creates the trust. So
customers actually need to see what
happened. They need to see logs. Uh they
need approvals, um controls, handoff
rules, that sort of thing.
And uh they need a way to test the agent
before it goes live. They need to know
basically why the agent did what it did.
So that wrapper is the SAS and the agent
actually lives in the phone system, the
inbox, the Slack channel, CRM. So the
dashboard can be really simple. Um but
the customer customer actually still
needs the control room. Um at least
that's what I'm noticing is working
right now. So for a restaurant phone
agent, the control room might be, you
know, call summaries or uh reservation
outcomes, missed human handoffs, that
sort of thing. Um, for a property
maintenance agent, maybe it's uh, you
know, tickets that have been created,
vendor routes or tenant updates, owner
approvals, that sort of thing. Um, and
that's really why eval matter a lot when
you're building an agent first uh
business. Um, because before you promise
autonomy,
you want to create a basically a small
test uh a test set is the best way to
think about it. So, you know, take 50
real examples of the job and then mark
the right answers like 50 calls, you
know, 50 leads, uh, maybe, you know, 50
maintenance requests, depending on what
it is. And then you want to run the
agent system against them. So, did it
classify the problem correctly? Did it
ask for the right missing information?
Did it use the right policy? This is
what's called an eval, right? your eval
set is, you know, it's basically like
the gym. You know, every time you change
the prompt, the model, the tools, the
workflow, the agent goes back through
the gym and and is able to, you know,
basically know what's good and know
what's bad. It's also like low-key a
really good sales asset because imagine
telling a property manager, you know, we
tested this on, you know, 50 of your old
maintenance requests. It routed 42
correctly, flagged six of them for human
review, and made two mistakes. Here are
the two mistakes, and here's how we fix
them. So, it just helps you actually
build trust, uh, especially with people
who are like who own boring businesses,
but who can actually really use some of
these agents. When you when you just are
transparent and open about these sorts
of things, you're going to build a lot
of trust with them. So, uh, the sixth
step, uh, on building an agent is you're
going to want to sell the pilot like
labor, and then you're going to want to
productize it. So, the fastest path is
usually a pilot where you manually do
the work with AI and then you productize
the repeated parts. I'll explain what I
mean by by that, but you know,
basically, I would start with three
customers in one niche. So the same
niche, same workflow, same pain and then
you sell the outcome. You actually want
to be like very very uh constrained on
this or else you're going to get bad
results. So if you're selling the
outcome, it's we will answer and qualify
your missed calls. We will triage your
maintenance request and then you charge
a setup fee and a simple like monthly
fee. um you can keep the pricing just
like easy to understand and then you can
add usage or outcome pricing once you
understand the value. I'm a huge
believer if you're, you know, listened
to the startup ideas podcast here and,
you know, you're a subscriber here, you
know, I I I really believe that outcome
pricing is the future of how a lot of
these agent first businesses and
software is going to be priced because,
you know, it just makes sense like, you
know, the customer only wants doesn't
want to pay for another seat for
something. So, uh, but don't just jump
there uh initially. Um, so you'll get
there and you have to have patience with
it a little bit. You know, the the
pricing model, like how do you think
about pricing uh something like this?
You know, maybe it's like a $1,500
setup, $1,500 setup, and then like
$1,000 a month for one workflow. Or
maybe it's like $2,000 setup plus $30
per qualified appointment. So that's
more the outcome base eventually. Or
$3,000 a month up to 500 handled
tickets. So the exact price actually
matters less than the learning. Uh you
basically want to find out what the
customer values and then uh where the
agent breaks uh what needs approval and
what would they miss if you took it
away. Pretty much the most important
question there is uh and then you build
the product around the repeated pattern.
So, if every roofer needs the same
emergency call script, service area
check, financing question, an estimate
follow-up, boom, you have a product. Um,
if every med spa needs lead scoring,
consultation booking, no show recovery,
um, post treatment follow-up, boom, you
have a product. So, this is agents ass.
You know, you earn the software by doing
the work first. Step seven is
distribution. You know, you're going to
want to get you need obviously you need
people to hear about the thing you're
building, hear about the agent, see it,
and be like, I need this. And how can
you do it? What are some tips to to be
thinking about this? Workflow tearowns
is what I'm seeing in real time that's
working really, really well. So, show
the old way of doing a process, right? A
call comes in, nobody answers. The
customer calls the next company or or
the CSR answers, a asks five questions,
checks the calendar, checks the service
area, books the job, you know, you know,
writes the notes, sends a reminder, and
then forgets to follow up. And then the
heart of the owner, of the manager just
absolutely breaks. And then you show the
agent way. A call comes in, an agent
answers, it asks the right questions, it
checks the service area, it checks the
urgency, it books the appointment, it
updates the CRM, it sends the
confirmation, it flags edge cases for a
human. That's the type of content that
works because the manager, the
executive, the owner feels that pain.
And you know, you want to be in the
business of selling painkillers, not
vitamins. And that's why I love these
building agent businesses because you
are, you know, if you do this right and
you go through some of these steps and
and these frameworks and this playbook
for coming up with an idea, building an
idea, you're building something that's
really really helping people. Like it is
very very valuable to them. And the only
way to really really get them to book a
call or do something is to show them
sort of make fun of the old way and then
show them the new way. Pick one
workflow, make the internet associate
you with it. And you know, the way I
think about it is you want to make the
checklist, you want to make the B
benchmark, make the tear down, make like
50 examples of this workflow post, and
you're going to be in the content game.
You know, a lot of people listening to
this, you know, don't want to create
content, and I totally understand, but,
you know, you have to create content
around this because it's just the, you
know, there's just a opportunity in
creating content. Um, and then you can
use some of those assets that are
starting to work and then put paid uh
paid ads uh around it. So, you know,
distribution, think about these these
tearowns, think about poking fun of the
old way, think about creating memes
around it, uh, and then creating
content, picking the winners, putting
paid ads against it. I would suggest
focusing on one platform to start. Um,
and uh, you know, I'm going to be doing
more episodes on just how do you how do
you get how do you get customers to your
your vibe coded apps and stuff like that
in the future. So stay tuned for that.
Um, but just you know how I'd be
thinking about it. The last step you
know the 0 to 100 plan like if I was
starting this from zero you know I feel
like people would want to know what
would be my plan. Um so I'll give you my
you know call it week four-week plan. Um
my first day what I would do like how to
build a business. How do you build an
agent business in 30 days? Okay. Day one
we pick a niche where missed work cost
money. We talked about this. Home
services, property management, you know,
insurance agencies. Day two, I would
interview 10 operators, ask them to
screen share the workflow, keep the
calls as research, and just watch them.
You can pay them for this, by the way.
Day three, pick one workflow with
frequency, pain, software access, and a
clear success metric. Day four, write
the agent spec, trigger, context, tools,
rules, handoffs, eval. Uh day five, run
it manually with AI. you know, use
claude or chatbt and copy and paste the
context, draft the output, uh, ask the
human to approve and you are testing
whether the AI helps before you build
the software. Day six, build that
smallest useful version. Uh, draft and
approve or triage is usually enough
here. Day seven, create the eval set
from 50 real examples. Week two, sell
two pilots in the same niche. Week
three, add the product wrapper, right?
The logs, the approvals, the settings,
the analytics, the handoffs, and use AI
to actually build that, you know,
software. I'd probably using something
like Clawude Design. And, you know,
assuming that Fable is live, using Fable
to actually code it up. Week four, I'm
publishing workflow tearowns. I'm
turning the pilots into proof and I'm
doubling down on my content strategy.
So, you know, while, you know, I I
should have mentioned this, but while
I'm doing all this, while I'm thinking
about building this business, I'm
building an audience all the way
throughout. And by the end of week four
four, I have formats that are working. I
know where to double down. I know where
I can spend money, pay paid money to
acquire customers. And that's when I,
you know, my second and third month, I'm
trying to understand what my LTV is. you
know, what are the channels that are
working, where can I double down on it,
and I keep going. I think that's the
episode. You know, basically where I'm
at is I think agents are the new SAS
because software is moving from help me
do the work to do the work with me. And
I think that a lot of people are just
they're not partaking in the shift. They
see the shift, they understand the
shift, you're listening to me, and
you're like, "Yeah, of course." But
they're not building they're not
building agent first businesses. Um, I
think the opportunity is basically to
find the smallest painful workflow that
repeats all day. Uh, in a niche that you
understand and make it disappear, you
know, answering a phone, booking a job,
triaging the ticket, uh, updating the
system, um, escalating that weird case.
Um, and I think there's a ton of money
to be made here and a ton of value to be
created. So, if you're watching this,
you're listening to this and you're
thinking, I want to build with AI, well,
start start with the job. You know, find
the job, shadow it, spec it, run it
manually, build the smallest useful
agent, sell the pilot, then productize
the repeatable parts. This is how you
build an agent that people will pay for.
And this is why I think building agents
is the new SAS. Hope this is helpful.
Hope this got the creative juices
flowing. People charge thousands of
dollars for this type of thing, but it
is free like always on the Startup Ideas
podcast. Let's I'll see you in the
comment section. I'll see you uh let's
talk and let me know what you want me to
cover next. If this is helpful and I
read every single comment on YouTube, I
appreciate every single like and
subscribe if you want more of this stuff
in your feed. Thank you and I'll see you
next